Armand Cezar Mathe

Cluj-Napoca, Cluj, Romania



me@cezarmathe.com



+40767989199



in linkedin.com/in/cezarmathe

Summary

Hi, I'm Cezar (or Cesar).

I design and build systems in the cloud. I work on software that must feel invisible to end-users, software that is capable, reliable and highly available. The software I usually build deals almost exclusively with other machines rather than humans. You guessed it - I design and build infrastructure, servers and microservices.

I was in high school when I decided to take a leap of faith, completely on my own, by joining Upwork. I landed my first client on a digital signage project involving a Raspberry Pi controller. Being a minor at that time, I was banned by the freelancing platform, but I resumed my mission shortly after "graduating" from childhood.

Getting into university, I landed my first big clients. I've built a Real-Time Bidding platform for Prodata Media Group. I've dealt with high-performance services - the servers participating in auctions - as well as other systems that performed various other business logic. It was here that I first had the chance to work with a system where a separation of the control plane and the data plane is highly desirable.

For Brightline Trains I've concentrated my efforts on refactoring an old, fat microservices model. My biggest contribution has been in re-writing an audit logging system that frequently failed. I've also made considerable contributions in building design documents and providing critical insights for design decisions targeting other microservices.

I'm currently maintaining the Real-Time Bidding platform for Prodata Media Group on a very minimal weekly schedule. Otherwise, I'm open to work!

Feel free to reach out to me here, on LinkedIn, or by email, for anything that may be of mutual interest.

Experience



🔐 Software Engineer

Kiwi Corporation Feb 2022 - Present (5 months +) Providing software services for my clients.



Freelance Software Engineer

ProData Media Group Jun 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month +) Building and maintaining a Real-Time Bidding platform.

Freelance Software Engineer

Brightline Trains Nov 2021 - May 2022 (7 months) Worked on refactoring and improving the existing e-commerce platform whilst ensuring its reliability and availability in the process.

Open Source Developer

Code for Romania

May 2020 - Jun 2020 (2 months)

Freelance Software Developer

Display Logic USA

Mar 2020 - Apr 2020 (2 months)

Improved the workflow of setting up a digital signage solution that leveraged a Raspberry Pi as the controller.

Freelance Software Developer

Display Logic USA

Apr 2019 - Sep 2019 (6 months)

Built a digital signage solution using a Raspberry Pi as the controller.

Education

Universitatea "Babeş-Bolyai" din Cluj-Napoca

Bachelor's degree, Business Information Systems 2020 - 2023



🤊 "Andrei Muresanu" National College, Dej

High School Diploma, Computer Science 2016 - 2020

Skills

Go (Programming Language) • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Rust (Programming Language) • Microservices • Shell Scripting • Linux • Distributed Systems • HashiCorp • Bazel • Real-Time Bidding (RTB)